Charles Cochrane

Software Engineer

Website: CharlesCochrane.com Github: github.com/charlesworth

Email: cochrane26@gmail.com

Profile

I'm a passionate and creative software engineer with a wide variety of experience. Hoping to work with interesting and experienced professionals to deliver quality, well designed software that people use and enjoy. A lover of learning with a strong team ethic, I help enable engineering hiring, mentorship, education and career development.

Employment History

Automata 2018-Present

Automata is a startup focused on bringing a disruptive robotic arm to market. I joined as an experienced hire to help scale and lead the engineering team and work full stack on the robot's internal control software and on Choreograph, it's 3D web based control platform. When not coding I focus on growing the team and offering mentorship and internal education.

Pusher 2017-2018

Pusher is a realtime communications API provider. I joined the startup to experience a smaller team and have more responsibility across a product. Began work on Pusher's data pipeline and later on Chatkit, a rich chat API service.

Independent Game Developer

2016-2017

Took time out to learn a new skill, game development, and gain experience managing a product and myself. Made "RacetronicVR", a time trial racing game for virtual reality headsets, which I released on Steam.

IBM 2013-2016

Worked on IBM's container registry and cloud hosting service, Bluemix, helping to design, create and run the service. Previously worked on their Cloud Foundry app hosting service and consulted closely with large clients.

Intel: Customer Quality and Reliability Engineer

2011-2012

13 month placement working with Intel's customers on hardware, software and manufacturing quality.

131 Commando Royal Engineers: Sapper

2009-2011

Trained Soldier and B3 Combat Engineer in the British Territorial Army.

Qualifications

Plymouth University: BEng Robotics

2009 - 2013

Received a 2:1 with honours. Included modules of programming, hardware design, electronics and robotics.

Skills and Knowledge

Languages

Most recently I've been mainly using Go, C++, JS and Python but consider myself as a generalist, having worked with many stacks and languages throughout my career.

General Tools

Linux, Git, SQL and NoSQL databases, Docker and Rkt, Kubernetes, Kafka, HAProxy and Nginx, ELK stack, Prometheus, Redis, Etcd, Vault, Jenkins, Protobuf, AWS/GCP/DO.

Interest areas

Distributed software and databases, robotics, scalability, networking, developer experience, education, game engine design.

Game Development

As a hobby, mainly using Unreal Engine 4, Godot or C++, comfortable with SDL2, OpenGL and webGL.

Interests